Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Payne and Helen Hay Whitney Family, 1826-1988; Series II
  - Whitney, Helen Hay
    - Miscellaneous, Circa 1898-1902 (Box 399, Folder 1)
  - Whitney, Payne
    - 972 5th Avenue, 1902 (Box 248, Folder 4)
    - Biographical, Circa 1930 (Box 248, Folder 5)
    - Business
      - American Creosoting Company, 1907 (Box 248, Folder 6)
      - Edgiston lease, 1902 (Box 248, Folder 7)
      - Granby properties, 1903 (Box 248, Folder 8)
      - Great Northern Paper Company, 1903-1907 (Box 248, Folder 9)
      - Northern Pacific Railway Company, 1903 (Box 248, Folder 10)
      - P. F. Collier and Son, 1909-1910 (Box 248, Folder 11)
      - Payne, Harry, legal files (brother), Circa 1900-1910 (Box 248, Folder 12)
      - Perry-Payne Company, 1901-1903 (Box 248, Folder 13)
      - Real estate, 1927-1969 (Box 248, Folder 14)
      - Securities, Undated (Box 248, Folder 15)
      - Stock certificates, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 248, Folder 16)
      - Waterbury Company, 1905-1907 (Box 248, Folder 17)
    - Certificates, Circa 1900-1927 (Box 248, Folder 18)
      - Oversize (Box 399, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1889-1926
      Discusses contracts and routine business operations.
      - Angell, James, 1905 (Box 249, Folder 1)
      - Astor, (William) Vincent, Circa 1926-1927 (Box 249, Folder 2)
      - Billings, Sherrard, 1892 (Box 249, Folder 3)
      - Bird, Oliver, 1911 (Box 249, Folder 4)
      - Breunan, M. P. H., 1903-1905 (Box 249, Folder 5)
      - Colson, Frederick, 1897-1898 (Box 249, Folder 6)
      - Cower, Margaret, 1912 (Box 249, Folder 7)
      - Dodge, Murray, 1889 (Box 249, Folder 8)
      - Friends, 1893-1926 (Box 249, Folder 9)
      - Great Northern Paper Company, 1902-1907 (Box 249, Folder 10)
      - Hay, John M., 1902 (Box 249, Folder 11)
      - Houghton Mifflin and Company, 1905 (Box 249, Folder 12)
      - Huntington, Samuel, 1905 (Box 249, Folder 13)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1922 (Box 249, Folder 14)
      - Paget, Almeric, 1895 (Box 249, Folder 15)
      - Paget, Pauline, 1892-1893 (Box 249, Folder 16)
      - Peabody, Endicott, 1893,1904, 1921 (Box 249, Folder 17)
      - Regan, T. J., 1903 (Box 249, Folder 18)
      - Rollins, F. S., 1904-1907 (Box 249, Folder 19-24)
      - Schieffiline, Baynard, 1921 (Box 249, Folder 25)
      - Sheffield, James, 1923 (Box 249, Folder 26)
      - Thilan, Edward, 1924 (Box 249, Folder 27)
      - White, Stanford, 1902 (Box 249, Folder 28)
      - Whitney, Flora (mother), 1892 (Box 249, Folder 29)
      - Whitney, Harry (brother), 1894 (Box 249, Folder 30)
      - Whitney, John Hay (son), 1911-1921 (Box 249, Folder 31)
      - Wickes, Forsyth, 1894 (Box 249, Folder 32)
    - Journal, 1907 (Box 250, Folder 1)
      Contains sporadic entries about daily activities.
    - New York Hospital, 1922-1924 (Box 250, Folder 2)
    - Passports, 1922-1924 (Box 250, Folder 3)
    - Yale University, 1894-1926 (Box 250, Folder 4)
  - Other family members (correspondence)
    - Hay, Clara Stone (mother to Helen Hay)
      - Bancroft, George, 1889 (Box 250, Folder 5)
      - Hay, John M., 1902-1904 (Box 250, Folder 6)
      - Whitney, Flora Payne, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 250, Folder 7)
    - Hay, Clarence from Clara Stone Hay, 1905 (Box 250, Folder 8)
    - Hay, Leonard from John M. Hay, 1903 (Box 250, Folder 9)
    - Payne, Oliver, 1889-1893, undated (Box 250, Folder 10)
    - Whitney, William Collins (Payne Whitney's father)
      - Hay, John M., 1901 (Box 250, Folder 11)
      - Peabody, Endicott, 1894 (Box 250, Folder 12)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1946-1998; Series III
  The series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains audio and video recordings. The majority of recordings pertain to John Hay Whitney and were generated as part of the research process for Jock: The Life and Times of John Hay Whitney, written by E. J. Kahn, Jr. The recordings include interviews with John Hay Whitney, his family, friends, and associates. Whitney's reminiscences are a valuable supplement to the papers and cover his upbringing; involvement in the motion picture industry; capture by the Germans in World War II; service as ambassador to the Court of St. James's; business pursuits; and philanthropic activities. Betsey Cushing Whitney, Kingman Brewster, Benno Schmidt, Jacob Javits, Walter Thayer, and others provide their memories and impressions of Whitney. The biography, Jock: The Life and Times of John Hay Whitney is read aloud by various family members and friends.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
  - Cushing, Harvey
    - "Cushing's 2000th Brain Operation" and "Harvey Cushing as I Knew Him", Undated; 1 (Box 251)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 251U)
    - "Dr. Cushing radio show", 1946; 1 (Box 252)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 252U)
    - Stamp
      - "Cushing Stamp Ceremony", 1988 September 20; 1 (Box 253)
      - "Cushing Stamp Events", Circa 1988; 1 (Box 254)
      - "Dr. Cushing Commemorative Stamp", 1988; 1 (Box 255)
    - The Story of Brain Surgery, [commercially produced], Circa 1990; 1 (Box 256)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 256U)
  - "Global Newspaper Centennial of the International Herald Tribune " [commercially produced], Undated; 1 (Box 257)
  - Harvey Cushing/John Hay Whitney Medical Library
    - "Harvey Cushing/John Hay Whitney Medical Library: the Dedication Ceremony", 1990 June 7; 1 (Box 258)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 258U)
    - "Songs of Hope", 1990 June 7; 1 (Box 259)
      Music from the library dedication.
  - "Mother's Day: a Family Reunion at Greentree"
    - Part 1, 1990 May 13; 1 (Box 260)
    - Part 2, 1990 May 13; 1 (Box 261)
      - Use copy (Parts 1 and 2), 1 (Box 261U)
  - "National Preservation Awards", 1998; 1 (Box 262)
  - "The Paris Liberty Flame: International Herald Tribune ", 1989 March 10; 1 (Box 263)
  - "Queen Mother's 90th Birthday", 1990; 1 (Box 264)
  - "The Voyage of the Observer ", Undated; 1 (Box 265)
  - Whitney, John Hay
    - By Whitney
      - "Farewell speech, American Ambassador to the Court of St. James's to the Pilgrims", 1961 January 11; 2 (Box 266–267)
        - Duplicating master (Box 266D–267D)
      - "In conversation on foundation and investments", Undated; 1 (Box 268)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 268U)
      - "In conversation on foundation, war, and Selznick", Undated; 1 (Box 269)
      - "In conversation on investments, movies, and plays", Undated; 1 (Box 270)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 270U)
      - "In conversation on investments, social concerns, estates, and racing", Undated; 1 (Box 271)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 271U)
      - "In conversation on philosophy, education and youth", Undated; 1 (Box 272)
        - Use copy, 2 (Box 272Ua–272Ub)
      - "On JHW and Investments" (Side A), Undated; 1 (Box 273)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 273Ua)
      - "In conversation: Walter Thayer and investments" (Side B), Undated; 1 (Box 273)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 273Ub)
      - "In conversation with Irene Selznick", 1981; 1 (Box 274)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 274U)
      - "Lovejoy address", 1964; 1 (Box 275)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 275U)
      - "On Gone with the Wind and Selznick International", Undated; 1 (Box 276)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 276U)
      - "On homes, smoking, and upbringing", Undated; 1 (Box 277)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 277U)
      - "On moving on as Ambassador", Undated; 1 (Box 278)
      - "On service as ambassador and family", Undated; 1 (Box 279)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 279U)
      - "On Yale", Undated; 1 (Box 280)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 280U)
      - "Story of capture by Germans as read by Jim Symington", Undated; 1 (Box 281)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 281U)
    - About Whitney
      - "Benno Schmidt on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 1 (Box 282)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 282U)
      - "Betsey Cushing Whitney on John Hay Whitney and Harvey Cushing", Undated; 1 (Box 283)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 283U)
      - "Jacob Javitz and Quinlan family on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 1 (Box 284)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 284U)
      - "Jack Fox on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 1 (Box 285)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 285U)
      - Jock: The Life and Times of John Hay Whitney
        - Author's Note-Forward and Dust Jacket read by E. J. Kahn, Jr., 1981; 1 (Box 286)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 286U)
        - Chapter 1, read by W. Scott Blanchard, 1981; 1 (Box 287)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 287U)
        - Chapter 2, read by Frank S. Streeter, 1981; 1 (Box 288)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 288U)
        - Chapter 3, read by W. Scott Blanchard, 1981; 1 (Box 289)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 289U)
        - Chapter 4, read by Peter di Bonaventura (grandson), 1981; 1 (Box 290)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 290U)
        - Chapter 5, read by Chris di Bonaventura (grandson), 1981; 1 (Box 291)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 291U)
        - Chapter 6, read by Charles Rees, 1981; 1 (Box 292)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 292U)
        - Chapter 7, read by W. Scott (Terry) Blanchard, 1981; 1 (Box 293)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 293U)
        - Chapter 8, read by Irene Selznick, 1981; 1 (Box 294)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 294U)
        - Chapter 9, read by William S. Paley, 1981; 1 (Box 295)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 295U)
        - Chapter 10, read by Frank Streeter, 1981; 1 (Box 296)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 296U)
        - Chapter 11, read by Kate Whitney (daughter), 1981; 1 (Box 297)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 297U)
        - Chapter 12, read by W. Scott Blanchard, 1981; 1 (Box 298)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 298U)
        - Chapter 13, read by Walter Cronkite, 1981; 1 (Box 299)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 299U)
        - Chapter 14, read by Kate Whitney (daughter), 1981; 1 (Box 300)
          - Use copy, 2 (Box 300Ua–300Ub)
        - Chapter 15, read by Walter Thayer, 1981; 1 (Box 301)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 301U)
        - Chapter 16, Part 1, read by Kathy Ritchie, 1981; 1 (Box 302)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 302U)
        - Chapter 16, Part 2, read by Kathy Ritchie, 1981; 1 (Box 303)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 303U)
        - Chapter 17, read by Ed Barlow, 1981; 1 (Box 304)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 304U)
        - Chapter 18, read by E. J. Kahn, Jr., 1981; 1 (Box 305)
          - Use copy, 1 (Box 305U)
      - John Hay Whitney biography, 1986 September 10; 1 (Box 306)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 306U)
      - John Hay Whitney biography, 1993 August 8; 1 (Box 307)
      - "The John Hay Whitney Collection National Gallery of Art", 1983; 1 (Box 308)
      - "John Hay Whitney funeral mass", 1982 February 12; 1 (Box 309)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 309U)
      - "Kingman Brewster on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 1 (Box 310)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 310U)
      - "Life as Jock's assistant," Spivak, Undated; 1 (Box 311)
        - Use copies, 3 (Box 311Ua–311Uc)
      - "Ogden Phipps on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 1 (Box 312)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 312U)
      - "Personal recollections of John Hay Whitney by cousin Jim Symington", Undated; 1 (Box 313)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 313U)
      - "Spivack on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 3 (Box 314–316)
        - Use copies, 3 (Box 314U–316U)
      - "Walter Thayer on John Hay Whitney", Undated; 1 (Box 317)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 317U)
      - "Walter Thayer on John Hay Whitney", Undated (December 18); 1 (Box 318)
        - Use copy, 1 (Box 318U)
- Photographs, 1854-2000; Series IV
  The series includes photographs in various formats documenting all aspects of Whitney family life, primarily for the years 1880 to 1995. The series also includes a small number of images of the Cushing and Hay families.
  The series is arranged in three sections: Events, Families\Individuals, and Topical.
  - Events
    - Brooks School tea, Circa 1990-1995 (Box 319, Folder 1)
    - Cushing Day
      - Brigham and Women's Hospital and Cushing/Whitney Library dedication at Yale University album, 1989-1990 (Box 319, Folder 2)
      - Greentree album, 1992 (Box 319, Folder 3)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, Texas, Founder's Day banquet, 1941 (Box 320, Folder 1)
    - Museum of Modern Art reception for the General Assembly of the United Nations, 1957 (Box 320, Folder 2)
    - New York Hospital groundbreaking, 1953 (Box 320, Folder 3)
    - Time Incorporated 40th Anniversary Celebration, 1963 (Box 320, Folder 4)
  - Families/Individuals
    - Cushing
      Includes images of Harvey Cushing, Betsey Cushing Whitney, Barbara Cushing Paley, and Mary Cushing Fosburgh.
      - General, Circa 1895, 1950-1960 (Box 321, Folder 1)
      - Cushing, Harvey, Circa 1854-1855, 1895 (Box 321, Folder 2)
    - Hay
      - Hay, Aldebert, Westminster School, Circa 1892-1894 (Box 321, Folder 3)
        - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 1)
      - Hay, John M.
        - General, 1876-1902 (Box 321, Folder 4)
          - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 2)
        - Adams, Henry, 1894 (Box 321, Folder 5)
        - Roosevelt, Theodore, Circa 1901-1905 (Box 321, Folder 6)
    - Roosevelt, 1930-1940 (Box 321, Folder 7)
      Contains images of Franklin D. Roosevelt, Sara Roosevelt, James Roosevelt, and Betsey Cushing Roosevelt.
      - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 3)
    - Whitney
      - Families
        - Whitney, Payne and Helen, family
          - General, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 321, Folder 8-9)
          - Children (John and Joan), 1903-1913 (Box 321, Folder 10-12)
          - Pets, Circa 1900-1920 (Box 321, Folder 13)
        - Whitney, John Hay and Betsey Cushing, family
          - General (Groups), Circa 1930-1995 (Box 322, Folder 1-9)
            - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 4-5)
          - Topical
            - Ambassadorial years, 1957-1961 (Box 323, Folder 1-9)
            - Birthdays
              - Whitney, John Hay
                - Fishers Island, Circa 1960-1970 (Box 324, Folder 1)
                - "To John Hay Whitney: toujours gai!" (photograph album), 1963 (Box 324, Folder 2)
                Compiled by Jinx and Tex McCrary.
              - Whitney, Kate, fiftieth birthday celebration at Greentree, 1986 February 16 (Box 324, Folder 3)
            - Children (Kate and Sara), Circa 1932-1960 (Box 324, Folder 4)
            - Chiucchini family (Kate's daughter and grandchildren), Circa 1990-2000 (Box 324, Folder 5)
            - Christmas luncheon album, 1992 (Box 324, Folder 6)
            - Cushing-Whitney family reunion, Circa 1990-2000 (Box 324, Folder 7)
            - Di Bonaventura
              - Family, Circa 1953-1960 (Box 324, Folder 8)
              - Wedding (Sara's wedding), 1953 (Box 324, Folder 9)
            - Friends
              - General, 1930-1960 (Box 324, Folder 10)
              - Eisenhower, Dwight D., Circa 1950-1960 (Box 324, Folder 11-12)
                - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 6)
            - Saratoga weekend album, 1949 (Box 324, Folder 13)
              Contains images of Whitney parties held over one weekend.
            - Shea Stadium, Circa 1962-1970 (Box 324, Folder 14)
              Includes images of John Hay Whitney, Joan Whitney Payson, and the di Bonaventura children.
            - Travel
              - Captiva Island, 1953 (Box 324, Folder 15-16)
                Includes images of the Whitneys, Paleys, and di Bonaventuras.
                - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 7)
              - France, 1954 (Box 325, Folder 1)
                Consists of images of the Whitney family visiting the site of John Hay Whitney's capture during World War II.
              - Scotland, Circa 1950-1960 (Box 325, Folder 2-3)
            - Wedding (John and Betsey), 1942 (Box 325, Folder 4-6)
        - Payson, Joan Whitney, family, Circa 1930-1940 (Box 326, Folder 1)
          - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 8)
        - Whitney family (multigenerational)
          Includes images of Whitney family members not listed individually, including Oliver Hazard Payne, Clara Stone Hay, William Collins Whitney; multigenerational group shots, and unidentified individuals.
          - General, Circa 1870-1960; no content (Box 326, Folder 2-3)
            - Oversize (Box 400, Folder 9)
            - (Whitney, William Collins) (Box 404, Folder 8)
          - Topical
            - Memorials, 1901-1986 (Box 326, Folder 4)
              Includes images of John Hay Whitney's memorial lot; Payne Whitney's gravestone and site; and a tree planted for John M. Hay.
            - Weddings (unidentified), Circa 1900-1930 (Box 401, Folder 1)
      - Individuals
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, Circa 1940-1990 (Box 326, Folder 5-11)
          Includes formal portraits, candid shots, and shots of hunting with members of the British Royal Family.
          - Oversize (Box 401, Folder 2-3)
        - Whitney, Helen Hay, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 327, Folder 1)
          - Oversize (Box 401, Folder 4)
        - Whitney, John Hay
          - General, Circa 1930-1950 (Box 327, Folder 2-3)
            - Oversize (Box 402, Folder 1)
          - Portraits, Circa 1930-1980 (Box 327, Folder 4-10)
            - Oversize (Box 402, Folder 2-3)
          - Topics/subjects
            - Altemus, Elizabeth, Circa 1930 (Box 328, Folder 1-2)
              Includes images of John Hay Whitney's and Altemus's wedding.
            - Ambassadorial years
              - General, 1957-1961 (Box 328, Folder 3-8)
              - Churchill, Winston, Circa 1955-1959 (Box 328, Folder 9)
              - Clubland photograph album, 1959 (Box 328, Folder 10)
                Consists of images of John Hay and Betsey Cushing Whitney's visit to Clubland, a boys' and girls' club in London.
            - Army
              - General, 1942-1945 (Box 329, Folder 1-2)
              - 20th Fighter Bomber Wing photograph album, Circa 1955 (Box 329, Folder 3)
                Images of the American Embassy's ceremony for the 20th Fighter Bomber Wing in London.
              - Site of John Hay Whitney capture photographs, Circa 1950-1959 (Box 329, Folder 4)
            - Associates, Circa 1930-1980 (Box 329, Folder 5-6)
              - Oversize (Box 403, Folder 1)
            - Boat and airplane, Circa 1940-1949 (Box 329, Folder 7)
              Consists of images of Whitney family boats and John Hay Whitney's plane, the Expediter.
              - Oversize (Box 403, Folder 2)
            - Bohemian Grove photograph album, Circa 1955 (Box 329, Folder 8)
              Documents visit to the Bohemian Club in Mount Rio, California.
            - Columbia University honorary degree, 1965 (Box 330, Folder 1-2)
            - English Speaking Union, 1962 (Box 330, Folder 3)
              Includes images of John Hay Whitney and Prince Philip at the English Speaking Union in Seattle.
            - Film industry
              - Hollywood, Circa 1930-1939 (Box 330, Folder 4-5)
                Includes images of John Hay Whitney with David O. Selznick and their associates, as well as images of Whitney and actors.
                - Oversize (Box 403, Folder 3)
              - Productions
                - Broken Dishes (play), 1929-1930 (Box 330, Folder 6)
                - Gone with the Wind, 1936-1937 (Box 330, Folder 7-8)
                Includes images of the film's premiere.
                - Jumbo (play), 1935-1936 (Box 330, Folder 9)
                - Life with Father (play), 1939 (Box 330, Folder 10)
            - Hunting, Circa 1920-1940 (Box 331, Folder 1)
            - J. H. Whitney and Company
              - Offices (oversize), 1959 (Box 403, Folder 4)
              - Partners, 1947-1966 (Box 331, Folder 2)
                - Oversize (Box 403, Folder 5)
            - New York Herald Tribune, 1961-1966 (Box 331, Folder 3-4)
              - Oversize (Box 403, Folder 6)
            - School
              - Groton School, 1918-1922 (Box 331, Folder 5)
                - Oversize (Box 413, Folder 1)
              - St. Bernard School, Circa 1910-1919 (Box 331, Folder 6)
              - Yale University
                - General, 1922-1926 (Box 331, Folder 7)
                - Scroll and Key album, Circa 1926 (Box 331, Folder 8)
              - Oversize (Box 404, Folder 1-3)
            - United States delegation-West Indies bases, 1960-1961 (Box 331, Folder 9)
              Contains images of John Hay Whitney and John F. Kennedy.
            - Yale University
              - Yale Corporation fellows, 1956-1964 (Box 331, Folder 10)
                - Oversize (Box 404, Folder 4)
              - 100 Year Association of New York Incorporated dinner, 1953 (Box 331, Folder 11)
        - Whitney, Payne
          - General, Circa 1885-1927 (Box 332, Folder 1)
          - Groton School, Circa 1890-1895 (Box 332, Folder 2)
          - Yale University (oversize), Circa 1898-1900 (Box 404, Folder 5)
  - Topical
    - Art collection, condition photographs, Circa 1980-2000
      - Art works
        Arranged alphabetically by artist name.
        - Alexander-Crawford (Box 333, Folder 1-11)
        - Cross-Manet (Box 334, Folder 1-15)
        - Marquet-Munnings (Box 335, Folder 1-9)
        - Picasso-Perlin (Box 336, Folder 1-8)
        - Redon-Van Dongen (Box 337, Folder 1-17)
        - Van Gogh-Zerbe (Box 338, Folder 1-5)
        - Unattributed (Box 338, Folder 6)
      - Disclaimed and sold (Box 338, Folder 7-9)
      - Jewels (Box 339, Folder 1-8)
    - Celebrities
      - General, Circa1930-1960 (Box 340, Folder 1)
        Includes images of Casey Stengel, Winston Churchill, Fred Astaire, and Queen Elizabeth.
      - Smith, E. L., Circa 1891 (Box 340, Folder 2)
        Includes an autographed photograph.
    - Equestrian
      - Horse racing, Circa 1920-1940 (Box 340, Folder 3-8)
        - Oversize (Box 404, Folder 6)
      - Horses owned by the Whitneys, Undated (Box 341, Folder 1-4)
      - Horses, Whitneys with, Circa 1900-1950 (Box 341, Folder 5)
      - Jockeys, Circa 1930-1939 (Box 341, Folder 6-8)
        Consists of images of jockeys on Whitney family horses at various racing events.
      - "Mr. Williams in Lexington, Kentucky", 1953 (Box 341, Folder 9)
        Includes images of horses at Greentree Stud farm in Lexington, Kentucky.
      - Polo, Circa 1920-1940 (Box 342, Folder 1-10)
      - Spectators, Whitneys as, Circa 1930-1960 (Box 343, Folder 1-4)
    - Properties
      Includes interior and exterior shots of Whitney family homes and estates.
      - General
        - Postcards, Circa 1900-1920 (Box 343, Folder 5)
          Includes images of various Whitney and Hay properties including Greenwood, Greentree, and the John M. Hay birthplace in Illinois.
        - Unidentified, Circa 1890-1990 (Box 343, Folder 6)
          - Oversize (Box 404, Folder 7)
      - 25 St. James's Place, Flat 3, 1984 (Box 343, Folder 7)
      - 163 East 63rd Street New York photograph album, Circa 1980 (Box 343, Folder 8)
      - 972 5th Ave., New York, New York
        Includes images of the Venetian Room.
        - Circa 1900-1910 (Box 343, Folder 9)
          - Oversize (Box 405, Folder 1-4)
        - Circa 1997-2000 (Box 343, Folder 10)
      - Beekman Place, New York, New York
        - Album 1, 1977-1980 (Box 344, Folder 1)
          Includes photographs of John Hay Whitney's birthday party in 1977 and photographs of Kate Whitney's family.
        - Albums 2 and 3, Circa 1980-1985 (Box 344, Folder 2-3)
          - Oversize (Box 406, Folder 1)
      - Fishers Island, New York
        - Circa 1940-1970 (Box 344, Folder 4-10)
        - Circa 1980, 1985-1992 (Box 345, Folder 1-5)
      - Greentree, Manhasset, New York
        - General
          - Circa 1940-2000 (undated) (Box 346, Folder 1-11)
            - Oversize (Box 406, Folder 2)
          - 1995 (Box 347, Folder 1-4)
        - Christmas, Circa 1990-2000 (Box 347, Folder 5)
        - Garden, 1990-1991, 1995 (Box 347, Folder 6-8)